Peter Spagnuolo Papers on Squatters' Rights TAM.336
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Peter Spagnuolo Papers on Squatters' Rights
circa 1980s-1990s
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Spagnuolo, Peter L.
TAM.336
3.5 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Peter Spagnuolo in 2006. The accession number associated with this gift is 2006.004.
Biographical / Historical
Peter Spagnuolo is a poet and author of The Squatter's Midden (2001) and Ten by Fourteen (2005). He was involved in the squatters' rights movement in New York City's East Village in the 1980s which culminated in Tompkins Square Park Police Riot of August 1988.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of subject files, clippings and legal documents relating to eviction of East Village Squatters as well as one videotape titled "By Any Means Necessary."
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.); Squatters -- New York (State) -- New York; Tompkins Square Park Riot, New York, N.Y., 1988.; Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.) -- Social conditions.; Spagnuolo, Peter L.
- 537/539 E. 13th Street Building Related Documents, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 537/539 E. 13th Street Homesteaders, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 537/539 E. 13th Street: Vacate Order, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 541 E. 13th Street Building Related Materials, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 541 E. 13th Street Exhibits and Other Documents, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder data_value_missing_a318d9b1550cbde8555a7def9a2aa2e0)
- 545 E. 13th Street Building Related Materials, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 6)
- ABC No Rio, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Action Folder, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Affidavits, Petitions - East 13th Street, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 9)
- BFC Construction Corporation, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Clippings/1, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Clippings/2, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Clippings/3, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder data_value_missing_c37852d72d74cecc0f957fba405e1da4)
- Community Land Trust, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence (with LISC, Enterprise Investors, POLs, CBOs), 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Council of the City of New York, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Devers, Larry, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Dora Collazo Plaza, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 18)
- East 13th Street Homesteaders' Coalition, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 19)
- East 13th Street Homesteaders' Coalition (Legal Documents)/1, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 20)
- East 13th Street Homesteaders' Coalition (Legal Documents)/2, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 21)
- East 13th Street Homesteaders' Coalition (Legal Documents)/3, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 22)
- East 13th Street Homesteaders' Coalition (Legal Documents)/4, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 23)
- East 13th Street Homesteaders' Coalition (Legal Documents)/5, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 24)
- East 13th Street Homesteaders' Coalition (Legal Documents)/6, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 25)
- East 13th Street Homesteaders' Coalition (Legal Documents)/7, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 26)
- East 13th Street Homesteaders' Coalition (Legal Documents)/8, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Emergency Order to Show Cause, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Enterprise Foundation, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 2)
- F.O.I.L. Letters, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Financial Documents: Checks, Invoices/1, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Financial Documents: Checks, Invoices/2, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Financial Documents: Checks, Invoices/2, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Financial Documents: Checks, Invoices/2, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Fliers Against Evictions, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Food Not Bombs, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Fran Luck Letter (and Anti-Antonio Pagan Broadsheet), 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Free Speech vs. U.S. Department of Justice and Federal Communications Commission: Affidavits, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Free Speech vs. U.S. Department of Justice and Federal Communications Commission: "Declaration of Judah Mansbach", 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Free Speech vs. U.S. Department of Justice and Federal Communications Commission:Injunctions, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Governor's Housing Conference, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 14)
- "Housing in the Balance: Seeking a Comprehensive Policy for City-Owned Housing" by Ann Henderson, Susan Saegert, Luis F. Sierra, Brian T. Sullivan, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 15)
- "Introduction to Housing" Reader by Professor Peter Marcuse, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Itiniaries (Emigrant 96' and others), 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Kunstler and Kuby, Law Office, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Legal Notices, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Lists of Names (Tenants, Witnesses, etc.), 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Local Initiatives Support Corporation (HSC), 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Lower East Side Coalition: Housing Development, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Lower East Side Rose, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Lower East Side Squatter Support Committee, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Mailing Lists, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Lower East Side Squatter Support Committee, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Microradio/Low Power FM, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Micro Radio/Low Power FM: Articles About, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 27)
- "Missing the Mark: Subsidizing Housing for the Priveleged, Displacing the Poor - An Analysis of the City's 10 Year-Plan", 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Mutual Housing Association, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Negotiating Team, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 30)
- New York City Department of Housing Preservation and Development, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 31)
- New York City Department of Housing Preservation and Development: LISC/Enterprise Program, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 32)
- New York City Department of Housing Preservation and Development: Owner's Affidavit of No Harrassment, 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Newspapers, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 1)
- "Nobodies Home", 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 1A)
- Notebooks, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Personal Documents (Medical, Notes), 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Photos, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 4A)
- Property Certificates and Agreements, Resale Certificates, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Radio Magazines, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Sociological Data, Articles, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Steal This Radio/1, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Steal This Radio/2, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Steal This Radio Players/1, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Steal This Radio Players/2, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Steal This Radio DJs and Programs, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Squat! 1990 Evictions, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Squat! 1990 Evictions - Clippings, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Support Letters for Coalition / Legal Committee, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 15)
- "Survival Without Rent", 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Technical Invoices, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 17)
- U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Vietnam Veterans, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 19)
- "World War 3" Activist Art Group, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 20)
- VHS, Floppy Disk, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 20A, Box Shared Tamiment 121)
- Oversized Newspaper Clippings (Box Shared Tamiment 081, Folder 6, Box Shared Tamiment 065, Folder 7)
- Posters (Box Shared Tamiment 069, Folder 6)